A Guide to the Edgar B. Young papers FA109
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Japan Society, 1973-1978; 2; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes; 3 Boxes 1.2 cubic feet
  - Building Operations, 1973-1976; 2
    - Japan Society House - General Files, 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 933)
    - Japan Society House - Renovation, 1974-1975 (Box 72, Folder 934)
  - Education, 1973-1978; 3
    Subseries 3 provides a glimpse of a few of the sponsored programs and conferences including the United States-Japan Intellectual Interchange Program (1973-1978).
    - Colloquia, Conferences, Meetings, Programs, 1974-1978 (Box 72, Folder 935)
    - "Japan Today", 1978 (Box 72, Folder 936)
    - United States-Japan Intellectual Interchange Program, 1973-1978 (Box 72, Folder 937)
  - Financial Administration, 1972-1977; 4
    - Committee on Budget and Finance, 1972-1977 (Box 72, Folder 938)
    - Pension Contract, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 939)
  - Fundraising, 1973-1977; 5
    - Fundraising, Grants, 1973-1977 (Box 72, Folder 940)
  - Public Relations, 1973-1978; 6
    Subseries 6 provides a brief look at some of the institution's 1970s activities through various brochures and newspaper clippings.
    - Brochures and Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 72, Folder 941)
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 72, Folder 942)
    - "Newsletter", 1973-1978 (Box 72, Folder 943)
- Edgar B. Young Photographs, 1964-1969; 3; 0.54 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box (wide)
  Edgar B. Young, a staff associate of John D. Rockefeller 3rd, played a vital role in the creation and early administration of Lincoln Center. Edgar B. Young was born April 27, 1908 in Anderson, IN. His academic credentials include an A.B. from DePauw University (1929) and post graduate degrees from the London School of Economics (Economics 1931), the University of Pennsylvania (Economics 1933), and American University (Public Administration 1935). Young was actively involved in the Lincoln Center project from its origin, participating in many of the early discussions while JDR 3rd served on the Exploratory Committee for a Musical Arts Center. After incorporation, Young became Lincoln Center's Secretary (1956-1962), and JDR 3rd became its first President (June 22, 1956-1961). Young also often served as a member of both the Executive and Education Committees at various points throughout his tenure with Lincoln Center. The Edgar B. Young collection documents Lincoln Center as a project fueled by the work and vision of volunteers and the non-profit sector of the economy. It serves as a model of successful urban renewal and collaboration between the private sector and various agencies of all levels of government. The photographs in this collection have been extracted from the print collection and relocated to Series 3.
  General note
  A total of one box of photographs have been extracted from the Edgar B. Young print collection. Photographs have been foldered; it has been noted on each folder where the photo was removed from. There is also a surrogate in place of the original in the print collection.
  File Plan
  When the Edgar B. Young photographs were initially extracted from the print collection, the images were designated as RAC photograph series 1073.
  RAC has since intellectually returned these materials to their original provenance, and designated the photographs as Edgar B. Young papers, Series 3.
  Physical labeling of the materials may temporarily remain as Series 1073. Future processing will rebox and relabel the contents to reflect their designation as Series 3, and take further steps to stabilize and preserve the items as necessary.
  Photographs
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Administration Traffic, 1965-1969 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    2 photos: Lincoln Center concourse level access plan with street grid
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Art (Box 84, Folder 2)
    Buildings: Juilliard: Sculpture: Masayuki Yagare, Untitled. Feb - March 1970 2 prints of the same image: JDR 3rd with Mr. Doi and two unidentified women, Nagare dedication ceremony, Lincoln Center, March 30, 1970
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Art (Box 84, Folder 3)
    Chermayeff and Lustig Contract, 1961 - 1965 (1973) Lincoln Center symbol design, Chermayeff & Geismer Associates, with correspondence of June 7, 1962
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Constituent Relations (Box 84, Folder 4)
    Library Museum of the Performing Arts: General Files, 1961 - 1962 (1971), Caption: Artist's conception of the Library-Museum for the Performing Arts in Lincoln Center. The view is of the faade on Amsterdam Avenue and the side elevation on 65th Street.
  - Lincoln Center. Inc. Education (Box 84, Folder 5)
    Choral Festival, May 1969 - 1972, 2 photos from the "Report on the Second International University Choral Festival" The Choral Festival was presented by the Education Department of Lincoln Center and held March 13-31, 1969.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Fundraising (Box 84, Folder 6)
    Public Participation Campaign March 8 - Sept 1960 (1972). 2 architectural models of Lincoln Center site from "Student Press Conference" Portfolio, April 7, 1960) One of these images is an early model of the Center with the following people gathered around it: Alicia Markova (ballerina), William Schuman (President of Juilliard), Martha Graham (modern dancer), Dorothy Pixley (Juilliard student), Lucine Amara (soprano), Rudolf Bing (Metropolitan Opera), Reginald Allen (Executive Director of Operations of Lincoln Center), George E. Judd, Jr. (Managing Director of the New York Philharmonic),Leonard Bernstein (Maestro of the New York Philharmonic), Robert Whitehead (theatrical producer), Julie Harris (actress).
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Fundraising (Box 84, Folder 7)
    Rockefeller Foundation: General Files, 1958-June 1960. 4 photos - architectural models and artist's sketches of Lincoln Center Plaza and the Metropolitan Opera House.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 8)
    Band Shell: Architectural Models and Sketches, 1960-1961 (1971).
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 9)
    Building Committee - General Files. November 1957-February 1958 (1971). Two copies of one photo - Consolidated Edison Plant in the block bounded by West End Avenue, Amsterdam Avenue, W. 65th Street and W. 66th Street.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 10)
    Federal Government: Negotiations re: Site and Contract with New York City, Jan-July 22, 1959 (1971-1976)1 photo - Lincoln statue proposed for Dante Square, February 1959.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 11)
    Federal Government: Negotiations re: Site and Contract with New York City, July 27-Aug 13, 1959 (1971-1976) 2 photos (models B1 and B2) accompanying the Revised Site Plan of Lincoln Center.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 12)
    Juilliard Building: Buildings, 1963-1968 (1971) 7 photos - models of the site across the street from Juilliard, July 30, 1964.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 13)
    Juilliard Building: Construction, 1967 (1970). 3 photos - From Collapse, March 9, 1967.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 14)
    Juilliard Building: Lincoln-Amsterdam Urban Renewal Project: High School of Music and Art; High School of Performing Arts, 1961 (1970). 1 photo - model of High School.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 15)
    Juilliard Building: Site Expansion, 1961-1964 (1971). 2 photos - including first exterior design model of the Juilliard School and Repertory Theater, May 1961.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 16)
    Metropolitan Opera House: Chandeliers (Austrian Gift), April-Aug 1964 (1971). 1 photo - a crystal chandelier mounted in a Luxemburg theater.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 17)
    Metropolitan Opera House: General Files, Nov 20, 1963-Dec 1964 (1971). 4 photos - "Opera Model Approved" February 26, 1964.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 18)
    New York State Theater: General Files, Sept 1961-March 1964 (1971). 1 photo - NYS Theater, Philip Johnson, Architect.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 19)
    New York State Theater: Cornerstone and Plaque, 1962-1963 (1971). 1 photo - New York State Theater, Orchestra Plan, Philip Johnson, Architect.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 20)
    Philharmonic Hall: Acoustics: General Files, 1959, 1962 (3 photos - 1. Max Abramovitz of the architectural firm Harrison and Abramovitz, Released May 27, 1962; Dr. Leo L. Beranek, president of Bolt, Beranek and Newman, acoustical Design consultant to Abramovitz for Philharmonic Hall, Released May 27, 1962; photo of an architectural design model of the auditorium of Philharmonic Hall.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 21)
    Philharmonic Hall: Green Room, 1962-1965 (1971). 2 photos - "Performing Arts" Steuben panels.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 22)
    Philharmonic Hall: Organ, May 1959-Mar 1962 (1971). 1 photo - "Four manual Odell console recently installed, William H. Odell" (1959).
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Planning and Construction (Box 84, Folder 23)
    Vivian Beaumont Theater: Design and Building, 1960-1961 (1971). 2 photos - Repertory Theater - Architectural Model and Site Plan.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 24)
    General Files, Jan-March 1958 (1973). 1 photo - EBY, Houghton and Spofford; received with correspondence from John W. McNulty, March 6, 1958.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 25)
    General Files, June-July 1958 (1973). 2 photos - Demolition Ceremony; received w/correspondence from John P. Davis, July 30, 1958.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 26)
    Groundbreaking Ceremony: Press Kit, May 14, 1959. 2 photos - artist's rendering of Philharmonic Hall and the entire Lincoln Center site.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 27)
    Library/Museum of the Performing Arts: Proposal Kit, Oct-Nov 1961. 2 photos - an artist's rendering of the Library-Museum and a site plan.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 28)
    Lincoln Center Neighborhood, n.d., 1963-1971. 1 photo - a color sketch of the neighborhood.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations, 1964-1967, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 29)
    Metropolitan Opera House, New York State Theater, Philharmonic Hall and Vivian Beaumont Theater.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 30)
    Press Release Kit: Fordham University to become part of Lincoln Square, January 20, 1959. 6 photos - sketches & site plans of the proposed Fordham University campus at Lincoln Square.
  - Lincoln Center, Inc. Public Relations (Box 84, Folder 31)
    Repertory Theater Design: Press Releases and Publicity, Nov 14, 1961. 12 photos - artist's renderings and models of the Repertory Theater.